他是我朋友 把女儿还我
He's a friend. Give me my daughter.
海德伍德博士 别动手 萨拉 不要
Dr. Headwood: Don't fight, Zarah! Don't!
他们抢走了莉安娜
They took Liana.
我们的使命对世界非常重要
Our mission is important to the world.
我们需要雪国列车来帮助 启动我们的营地
We need Snowpiercer to help launch our compound.
每月来这里领取你的蓝图和数据
Come by here monthly to pickup your blueprints and data.
我需要为我的宝贝女儿而战
I need to fight for my baby girl.
你可以拿走引擎
You can take the engine.
没有大爱丽丝 我们还能撑多久
How much longer can we last without Big Alice?
最好希望莱顿快点回来
We better hope Layton comes back soon.
让我们换... 莉安娜换大爱丽丝
Let's trade... Liana for Big Alice.
我永远不会忘记我们的第一次革命
I'll never forget our first revolution.
冰封的世界中响起了震耳欲聋的寂静
The deafening silence of a frozen world.
感觉好几个星期没人说一句话
No one said a word for what felt like weeks.
在寂静中 我们面对自己做出的选择
And in the quiet, we face the choices we have made.
韦尔斯特德小姐
Ah, Miss Wellstead.
很高兴 终于见到真人了
So nice to finally meet in person.
重要的不是我们救了多少人
It didn't matter that we'd saved so many.
而是那些我们失去的人
We only focused on the ones we'd lost.
分道扬镳的决定带来了持久的后果
Split decisions with lasting consequences.
嘿
Hey.
乔西在哪儿
Where's Josie?
条件很简单
The terms are simple.
我们遵守大爱丽丝换莉安娜的交易
Liana for Big Alice.
你抢走了一个孩子
You... you stole a child.
You stole a child!
嘿 别碰她
Hey, get your hands off her.
别碰她
Get off!
好了 够了
All right, that's enough.
回去找莱顿 把我的条件告诉他
Go back to Layton, deliver the message.
去你的
Screw you.
让我跟她谈谈
Let me talk to her. Please.
给你一分钟
You have one minute.
你不能告诉莱顿这个交易
You can't take this deal to Layton.
莉安娜在他们手上
They have Liana.
哪怕米利厄斯兑现他的承诺
Listen, even if Milius comes through with his promise,
我们要为他奉上两个列车头
we'll be giving him both engines.
值得吗
Is it worth it?
我想说的是 有你和莱顿带头
What I'm saying is with you and Layton leading the charge,
我们就有机会夺回列车头
we actually have a shot at winning this train back.
天啊 我不确定 本
God, I don't know, Ben.
乔西 这趟列车上的人已经受够了
Josie, the people on this train have suffered enough.
我们需要反击
We need to fight back.
时间到了
Time's up.
有人会护送你回去
Wolf will escort you.
你想劝她别这么做
Tried to talk her out of it, huh?
你不觉得这有点虚伪吗 因为梅兰妮
It's a bit hypocritical, don't you think, given that Melanie
把列车头留给了你
spared you for the Engine?
是 看看给我们带来了什么结果
Yeah. Look where that got us.
我们花了很长时间才搞清楚
It took us a long time to figure out
如何在这个世界上生存 如何压抑我们的怨恨
how to move through the world, how to bottle our resentment,
做出艰难的决定 但我们做到了
make the tough calls, but we did
因为总有人要负重前行 哪怕是在
because someone always has to, even when it was
雪国列车上 有1001节车厢那么长的列车
Snowpiercer, 1,001 cars long.
本是对的
Ben's right.
我们应该战斗
We should fight.
听着 我在精神上支持你 但是莉安娜怎么办
Look, I'm with you in spirit, but the risk to Liana...
不管我们是否接受这个交易 她都有危险
She's at risk whether we take the deal or not.
你又没在这里待过
You haven't been here.
这些人 他们太不人道了
These people, they're inhuman.
听着 她都不在列车上
Look, She's not even on the train.
我们至少应该让她
We should at least get to her.
我们甚至不知道她是否还活着
We don't even know if she's alive.
我需要她活着的证据
I need proof.
收到
Copy.
我们还有多远
How far out are we?
很好 我们在范围内了
Oh, good. We're in range.
什么范围
For what?
你的朋友把消息传给了莱顿
Your friend passed the message on to Layton.
看来他也有一些自己的条件
Seems he has a few demands of his own.
那是肯定的
Wouldn't expect anything less.
他拐走了他的孩子
You took his child.
每个人都有弱点
Everyone has their weakness.
你认为爱是一种弱点
You think love is a weakness?
最容易被人看破的弱点
Most predictable one there is.
那你显然从来没有感觉过爱
Then you've obviously never felt it.
我当然感受过
Of course I have.
你以为我是怎么吸取这个教训的
How do you think I learned that lesson?
有动静
There's movement.
我在找安德烈·莱顿
I'm looking for Andre Layton.
你的援军呢
Where's your backup?
手里有筹码 就不需要援军
You don't need backup when you have leverage.
你是这列车上的传奇
You're something of a legend on this train.
人们谈论你的方式 是你激励了他们
The way people talk about you, you inspire them.
我女儿换列车头 为什么
My daughter for the Engine. Why?
这不是个人恩怨
Wasn't personal.
我们所做的工作是为了拯救世界
The work we're doing is going to save the world.
听着 你省了征召演讲吧
Look, you can skip the recruitment speech.
我不会相信的
I'm not signing up.
当需要我们时 我们都挺身而出了
We all got drafted when the cold came.
萨拉不是士兵
Zarah wasn't a soldier.
那只是个不幸的事故
That was an unfortunate accident.
你难道不想看到你的女儿成长的世界是
Don't you want to see your daughter grow up in a world...
你到底想不想交出我女儿
Are you going to give me what I want or not?
另一趟列车上的女人 露丝
The woman on the other train, Ruth,
如果你让她连接在一起 她会照做吗
if you ask her to connect, will she do it?
如果你不交出我女儿 也无所谓了
It doesn't matter if you don't deliver.
我知道 虽然对你来说可能意义不大
Well, I know it may not mean much to you,
但我是个言出必行的人
but I'm a man of my word.
喂
Hello?
喂 海德伍德医生
Hello, Dr. Headwood.
他还还吗
Is he there?
万事俱备 只等你了
Everything's ready when you are.
你叫爸爸吗
Can you say, Papa?
叫爸爸
Say Papa.
快啊 莉安娜
Come on, Liana.
叫爸爸
Say Papa.
快啊 宝贝
Come on, Li-Li.
爸爸
Papa.
宝贝 宝贝 莉安娜 爸爸来了
Baby, baby... Liana, Daddy's coming.
别害怕 等等
Don't be scared. Hold on.
爸爸 莉安娜
Daddy's... Liana?
嘿
Hey.
她在他们手上
They have her.
好吧 那我们就把她赎回来
Well, then we'll get her back.
列车不小
It's a big train.
他们可能还在搜寻
They could still be searching or hiding.
或者他们被抓住了
Or they've been caught and we're
我们正走向设好的埋伏
headed right for a bushwhack.
或者 我们要撤退吗
Or that. So do we back off?
不行
No.
现在还不行
You can't, not yet.
露丝 亚历克斯 你们在吗
Ruth, Alex, are you there?
我很惊讶 你居然在用他们的官方通话线路 安德烈
Surprised to hear you on the official line, Andre.
我和上将在一起
I'm with the Admiral.
你好啊
Hello again.
他向你问好
He says hi.
上将
Admiral.
我需要你连接两辆列车
I need you to connect the trains.
我为什么要那么做呢 莉安娜在他们手上
And why would I do that? They have Liana.
她没在雪国列车上 但我听到了她的声音
She's not on Snowpiercer but I heard her voice.
她还好吗
And she's all right?
她和海德伍德在一起
She's with Headwood.
他们说会把她还给我
They say they will give her back to us
条件是我们交出大爱丽丝
when we give them Big Alice.
如果我们真的连接了 唯一能再分离的方法是
If we connect, the only way to force a separation is...
就是系统覆写 我知道
Manual override. I remember.
安德烈
Andre...
我得把她找回来 好吗
Ruth, I need to get her back. OK?
我保证 剩下的我们以后会解决的
We will figure out the rest later. I promise.
露丝 求你了
Ruth, please.
这就是我们行动的原因 对吧
This is the whole reason that we're doing this, right?
救出莉安娜
To save Liana?
是的 没错
Yeah. Yes, it is.
动手吧
Do it.
现在连接大爱丽丝
Connecting Big Alice now.
谢谢你 露丝
Thank you, Ruth.
好的 亚历克斯 慢慢来
All right, Alex. Nice and slow.
小心点
Watch your back, Ben.
连接系统启动
Coupling system initiated.
注意点
Kiss, kiss.
好了吗
Done?
差不多了 大爱丽丝
Just about. Big Alice.
座位系统受控
Ceding system control.
固定好了
They're locked in.
别担心 莱顿 很快就会结束的
Don't worry, Layton. This will all be over soon.
我希望能有一个更快乐的重聚
I was hoping for a happier reunion.
我也一样
Likewise.
你知道 我不得不接受这笔交易
You know I had to take the deal, right?
我不知道该怎么解释 但相信我 我知道该做什么
No need to explain. Believe me, I know.
你刚才在上边忙什么呢
What were you working on back there in the Engine?
只是一点保险措施 看他们能不能抓到你
Just a bit of insurance. See if they catch on.
后面是什么
What's back there?
这几个月以来 梅兰妮一直在这里工作
This is where Mel's been working all these months.
你去过那里吗
You ever been in there?
没
Never.
将军命令我协助你进行登车检查
Hello. The Admiral has instructed me to aid in your debarkation.
你们会被押送进筒仓 然后挨个进行检查
You'll be escorted into the Silo and attended to one by one.
第一个 安德烈·莱顿
First up, Andre Layton.
好吧
All right.
请脱下衣服 丢弃所有物品 等待清理程序
Please strip down, discard all belongings, and await decon procedure.
丢弃所有物品 否则将被没收 然后被焚毁
Discard all belongings or they will be confiscated and burned.
登上平台 等待清理程序
Now step onto the platform and await decon procedure.
不
No.
你个婊子
Son of a bitch!
我想和将军讲话
I want to speak to the Admiral.
你能带我去见他吗
Can you take me to him?
这几层出什么事了
What happened to these floors?
被攻占了吗
They get breached?
不说话 很好
Good talk.
他们为什么把你们都带到这里来
Why did they bring all of you here?
显然我们被盯上了
We're on some list, apparently.
嘿
Hey.
我都不确定你能同意连接
Wasn't sure you were going to connect.
我差点没同意
I almost didn't.
最终还是同意了这笔交易 我们想办法离开这吧
Now let's find Liana and find a way out of here, shall we?
对
Yeah.
开得不错 工程师
Nice driving, Engineer.
你之前有点用力过猛了
You know, I thought you came in a touch too rich.
你知道这地方的作用吗
You got any idea of the layout of this place?
原来我和梅兰妮还有接触的时候
Well, back when me and Mel were in touch,
她说这里为了禁锢你 搞乱你的大脑
she said it was designed to keep you confined,
然后失去时间感
confused with no sense of time.
这是怎么了
What's that about?
列车连接到电网上了
The train is connected to a power grid.
它可以先待机 但只能待机三个小时 然后就不受我们控制了
It can idle but for three hours only, and then it's gone.
我们还有多少时间
And how long do we have?
2小时36分钟
Two hours and 36 minutes.
2个小时36分钟 完成交易然后逃走
Two hours and 36 minutes to find Liana and get the hell out of here.
我们可以这么做
We can do that.
当然 我们可以的
Sure, we can do it.
乔西和你们谁在一起吗
Was Josie with any of you?
她比我先进去 她应该出来了
She went in before me. She should be here.
大家晚上好
Good evening, everyone.
乔西在哪儿
Where's Jose?
你所有的问题都会得到解答 但首先
All your questions will be answered, but first...
但首先我想感谢你所做的一切
but first, I want to thank you for everything you've done.
我知道这不容易 但成功是需要牺牲的
I know it hasn't been easy, but good work takes sacrifice.
你们中的一些人知道 我们在这里待了很多年
As some of you know, we've been down here
目的是让世界回暖
for years on a mission to warm the world.
现在我们有了两个列车头
Now that we have both engines, that mission
这个任务终于可以完成了
can finally be accomplished.
你的任务里包括新伊甸园吗
Does your mission include New Eden,
因为没有大爱丽丝 它就无法生存
because it won't survive without Big Alice.
这正是我们这么做的原因
That's precisely why we're doing this.
依靠永动机和它的能量输出 那只是临终关怀
Relying on eternal engines and energy output, it's hospice.
为了维持生命的最后挣扎而已
It's a last grasp at life support.
而我们是在寻找解决办法
We're looking for a cure.
梅兰妮在哪儿
And where's Melanie?
怎么不是她来告诉我们
Why isn't she here to tell us this?
她去收集气候信息了
She's off base collecting climate data.
不在基地 很快回来
She'll be back soon.
所以是她让我们都来这儿的
Is that we're all here, because Melanie requested it?
不算是吧
Not exactly.
你应该不想知道这个
This is the part you're not going to like.
我要杀了你 去死吧
You're dead. You're dead.
拦住他 我杀了你
No. You aren't safe.
我要杀了你
I'll kill you.
把女儿还我
Give me back my daughter, Milius.
你答应过的
You promised!
把他也带走
Take him to 12.
你答应过的
You promised!
把他拉开
Give her to me!
欢迎回来
Welcome home.
怎么看着不高兴 这是怎么回事
Come now. Why the long faces? What's all this about?
安东尼奥发现我躺在铁轨上
Well, Anton here found me on the tracks,
把我带了回来 你们不是让我出去吗
picked me up after you'd all sent me out into the cold,
当然 没有你 亚历克斯 都不确定你在哪儿
except you, Alex. Not sure where you were in all that.
别废话 你把梅兰妮怎么了
Enough of this shit. What have you done with Melanie?
别激动 本
Oh, come on, Ben.
我们现在是一队的 包括梅兰妮
We're on the same side now, even Melanie.
不过奥黛丽在哪儿呢 我想一次告诉所有人
Where's Audrey? I wanted to get you all in one go.
去死吧
Go to hell.
差点 但死不好玩
I did. Wasn't much fun.
是你 杀了负责永动机的莉安娜
So it was you. Liana for the Engine?
真是你一贯的作风
Classic Wilford.
这是最简单的办法
It was the simplest solution.
萨拉死了
Zarah died. All right.
行了 够了
That's enough. Yes.
你们稍后再重新认识吧
You can all get reacquainted later.
好的 期待和大家一起合作
Of course. I look forward to collaborating with you all again.
安东尼奥
Anton.
约瑟夫
Joseph.
列车开了你们才能走
You're to sit tight until the trains have departed,
我们会给你戴上手环 带你们到新住处
then you'll be processed for wristbands and shown to your new accommodations.
所以我们要待在这儿
So we're to stay here?
直到任务结束
Just until the mission is completed.
下次你们下车时
The next time you leave this place,
列车已到最后的伊甸园
the entire world will be New Eden.
所以我们就是囚犯
So we're prisoners.
是乘客
You're guests.
是呢 你的卫兵只是带莱顿去做水疗了
Oh yeah? Your Wolf take Layton to the spa?
只是找个地方平静下
Somewhere else to calm down.
现在你把我们都藏在这里
So now that you've got us all tucked away in here,
乘客们怎么办
what happens to our passengers?
他们会继续在列车上干活
They'll continue their work on the train.
我们马上就到了 差最后一点
We're almost there. Just one last push.
将军 你被利用了
Admiral, you are being played.
你一秒都不能相信威尔福德
You can't trust Mr. Wilford, not for one second.
他们的表情 他扑向我的样子 像疯子一样
The look on their faces, the way he lunged at me like a wraith.
我说了会成的 对吧
I said it would work, didn't I?
一点小建议
Well, I do have one last bit of advice.
你知道吗
Do you now?
对 别让莱顿见他女儿
Yes. I wouldn't let Layton see his daughter just yet.
这些人都听他的
These people have a habit of rallying around him.
还是把他们分开吧 以防万一
Let's keep them separated just in case, you know.
好主意 我会好好考虑
It's a good idea. I'll take it under consideration.
谢谢您 对了 我们最后说的那件事
Thank you. Oh, and about that... that last thing we discussed.
给你两个小时
You have two hours.
好
Right.
好好想想
Make them count.
告诉我 他们都被带到哪儿去了
Hm. Just tell me where they took the others, will you?
你感觉不到吗
You really can't feel that?
你的症状恶化得很快
Your symptoms have progressed quite rapidly.
部分韧带撕裂 非常痛
Partial ligament tear. It's very painful.
你四肢都没有知觉吗
Has the desensitization spread to all of your extremities?
谢谢医生 我会好好照顾她的
Thank you, doctor. I'll see to her.
别过来
You stay away from me.
乔西 你想错了
Josie, you're making an assumption.
你是个绑匪 一个杀手 不
You're a kidnapper. No. A killer. No.
我只是想帮她
I was trying to help.
再走一步 我就掐死她
One more step and I'll snap her neck.
乔西 求你了
Josie, please.
萨拉的死是个意外
Zarah's death was an error.
她摔下去了 如果她听我的
She fell. If only she'd listened to me.
我是想救莉安娜
I was trying to save Liana.
乔西 求你了
Josie, please.
我们是为了救她才去的筒仓 才到了这儿
That is why we came to the Silo. It's why I'm here.
乔西 莉安娜需要你的帮助
Josie, Liana needs your help.
她需要你帮她
She needs your help.
她怎么了
What's wrong with her?
真是乱了套了
This is a right mess.
我就不该把列车连起来
I never should have connected those trains.
我们本来是想着帮莱顿
You were just trying to help Layton.
结果真好
Well, a fat lot of good it did.
莱顿被带走了 威尔福德死而复生
Layton's dragged away and Wilford's back from the dead.
我们都乱了手脚
We were completely blindsided.
对 也许这就是他们跟我们切断联系的原因
Yeah. It's probably why they cut us off months back.
肯定是梅兰妮发现后气坏了 就跟我们现在一样
No doubt when Melanie found out, she was just as livid as we are now.
谁知道这事她究竟有没有参与
Well, who's to say she's even still involved?
本之前收到的她的蓝图
Well, Ben's been getting her blueprints.
也许是威尔福德的 不是梅兰妮
They could be Wilford's plans, not Melanie's.
不 我能认出来 梅兰妮的完全不同
No. I'd know Mel's work.
我不敢相信她又和他合作了
I can't believe she'd work with him again.
不管威尔福德到底演了什么角色 这项使命还是有意义的
Whatever role Wilford's playing into this, the mission still has merit.
是吗 那你也想参加吗
Oh, I'm sorry. Would you like to enlist?
我没说我同意他们的方法 露丝
I'm not saying I agree with their methods, Ruth.
我是说这个地方 以及梅兰妮在这儿的工作
I'm saying that this place, the work that Melanie's doing
可以让我们看清自己的处境
here, it could help us realize if our pocket is stable or not.
真聪明 那我们就坐下放松 等他回来
Oh, great. So we just sit back and relax and wait for the sun to return,
动动脑子 想想怎么把列车头重新夺回来
or we figure out how to get the Engine back for the people we care about.
我要去看看威尔福德
I'm going to see Wilford. Hey.
等等 别急
Hold on.
我听听他怎么说 想办法再谋划
I'm going to hear what he has to say.
没事 他没什么能控制我了
And I'm going to try to orchestrate something from the outside. Alex, no.
没事的
I'll be fine.
不行 太冒险了
He doesn't have a hold on me anymore.
这主意可不好 我不赞同
It's a bad idea. I don't like it.
你有何高见
He'll see me.
我有个请求
I have a request.
给
Here.
你应该想要这个
I thought you might want that back.
你想要我干什么
What do you want with me?
礼貌点 我只想做个好人
Civility. I'm trying to play nice here.
只要你态度好 我会让你见女儿的
If you play nice, too, I'll let you see your daughter.
她在这儿吗
Is she even here?
当然 只要你耐心等待
Yes. You just have to be patient.
如果不让我见莉安娜 至少让我见见乔西
If you won't let me see Liana, at least take me to Josie.
她在你上车时耍的小把戏中受伤了 正在治疗
She was injured in that little stunt you pulled getting on the train, so she's being treated.
等她好了 你就能见她
You can see her when she's done.
你或许有一两次机会占上风
Yeah. You might get a swing in, maybe two,
但绝对不足以逃走
not enough to escape, but
但你真正的目的也不是逃 对吧
that's not really what you're after, is it?
我只想看看我的家人
All I want is my family.
顺便杀了威尔福德报仇
And maybe a little vengeance on Wilford, too.
我说得对吗
Am I right?
我想说
I'll tell you what.
只要你乖乖配合 任务完成后
You play nice, when the mission's complete,
我给你机会杀了他
maybe I'll let you take a shot at him.
这些调整 我还是不相信列车能承受火箭的反冲
These adjustments... I'm still unconvinced the train can withstand the rocket's blowback.
天哪 尼玛 这是你第一次上大爱丽丝号
Oh, for God's sake, Nima, this is your first time on Big Alice.
别太担心
Take a load off.
能不能先欢迎我回来
Her wares are welcoming.
欢迎
Yes.
谢谢
Thank you.
这是工程学的奇迹
A feat of engineering.
但这些调整
But the adjustments... Yes.
好 我知道了
Yes. I know.
你就是没法和人聊天 是吗
You were never one for conversation, were you?
大爱丽丝能承受的 我们只需要调整下副火车头
Big Alice can handle it. All we need to do is modify the sub-Engine.
已经开始调整了
Conversions are already underway.
你什么时候开始跑腿了
Since when were you an errand boy?
你记得你干的是更大的事
Surely, you have more important matters to attend to.
我和将军发生了分歧
I had a little disagreement with the admiral.
正在接受惩罚
I'm serving penance.
他是个粗人 品不了细糠
He's a bull. He doesn't understand the finesse of what we do.
亚历克斯 真把这儿当自己家了
Ah, Alex. I see you've made yourself at home.
可以先回避一下吗 尼玛
Would you excuse us, Nima?
尼玛 家庭口角 你理解一下
Nima, family squabbles. I'm sure you understand.
这儿改造得挺不错的
You've done quite the remodel, I must say.
被我扔了
I threw them out.
哟 即便对你来说 也有点残忍了
Oh, that's cruel, even for you.
你在这里做什么 你到底想要干什么
What are you doing here? What's your end game?
我想帮助人们 拯救世界
I'm helping them save the world.
在我面前别装了 都知道你不在乎这个世界
Dubs, it's me. OK? We both know that you don't care about the world.
亚历克斯 我们在做一些伟大的事情
We are doing something extraordinary on the train,
伟大到连你妈妈也会觉得不可能
Alex, something even your mother never thought possible.
你一点也不好奇吗
Aren't you the least bit curious about it?
我可以带你去实验室里看计划图
I can show you the schematics if you want in your mother's lab.
看看工作进展如何
You could check our work.
你一直是我最喜欢的徒弟
You always were my favorite protege.
你还想要我做什么吗
Or is there somewhere else you need to be?
快点
Think fast.
我就知道你不会扔了它
I knew you wouldn't toss it.
没事 山姆 我可以
It's all right, Sam. I've got her.
一小时后发车
Departure in one hour.
不 过来 这边
No. No. Come along this way. This way.
怎么做到的 魔法吗
What is this, a magic trick?
走小路吧
Just a little shortcut.
你先走
After you.
你把这里建得挺复杂
You really got this place wired, huh?
乔西怎么了 是不是你干的
What happened to Josie? Was that you?
亚历克斯 你刚才不是很友好吗
Oh, Alex. You were doing so well, pretending you'd
假装忘了朋友的存在
forgotten about your friends.
你要对他们做什么
What do you want with them anyway?
这是要清楚轨道的障碍吗
Is this revenge for the track scaler?
我早不记恨这些了
I'm past all that. Are you?
是吗 你就算不偷莱顿的孩子 也能拿走火车头的
Because you could have taken the Engine without stealing Layton's kid.
我就是太慈悲了
Call me sentimental.
所以莉安娜也是你杀的
So you took Liana for yourself then?
这是一种对称的美 你不觉得吗
There's a certain symmetry to it, isn't there?
你不觉得吗
Don't you think?
再说了 我就是爱这种戏剧效果
Besides, I do enjoy a good twist of the knife.
走吧
Come.
她不会回来了
She's not coming back.
这还不确定
We don't know that.
我们需要一个新计划
We need another plan.
对
Yeah.
我满脑子都是大家要回最后的伊甸园了
All I can think about is everyone back at New Eden.
那里会阳光明媚
What's it like? 75 and sunny?
不
No.
仍然会很冷 生活会很难
It's still cold, hard living,
但终于能自己掌控了
but it's ours.
重见天日 踏上坚实的地面
Being outside again, and stepping onto solid ground,
抬起头 就是无垠的蓝天
and looking up and seeing nothing but sky,
忘记这一切艰难
I'd forgot what that was like.
听起来真好
Sounds nice.
是这样的
Yeah, it does.
知道吗 我觉得该动手了
You know what? I think it's time to go.
和梅兰妮一起做雪国列车 我最喜欢的就是开头
My favorite thing about building Snowpiercer with Mel was right at the beginning
她就像是一具躯壳
when she was just a hull.
露出本质的东西
Something visceral about it,
所有内脏一清二楚
all the parts exposed.
所以里面的东西能带我们出去吗
Those insides are going to get us out of here?
我看看
Let's see.
真是个工程师
Engineer.
走了 小心脚下
Come on. On your feet.
这边
This way.
嘿 别动
Hey, don't move.
拿上他的腕带
Get his wristband.
我们把他藏好
Let's get him out of here.
莉安娜
Liana.
对下时间
Time check?
大约34分钟
34 minutes.
知道吗
Right. You know what?
我们得分头行动 你在说什么
We need to split up. What are you talking about?
我们时间不够了
There's not enough time left.
你俩去开大爱丽丝 我会找到莱顿和其他人的
You two take Big Alice. I'll find Layton and the others.
不 我们一起行动
No. We stick together.
你需要工程师来开动列车 对吗
Look, you need an Engineer to drive, right?
你跟他待一起 走到上面的可能性更大
And he's more likely to get to the top if you go with him.
露丝 无意冒犯 但我觉得
Ruth, no offense, but I don't think...
蒂尔的事后我已经进步很多了 贝丝
I've come a long way since the Teals, Bess.
我一个人可以的
I can hold my own.
你们俩得把火车头弄好 回到新伊甸园
You two need to get that Engine back to New Eden.
这是我们最好的机会了
It's our best shot.
那里的人还指望我们呢
Everyone there is relying on us.
那雪国列车怎么办
What about Snowpiercer?
只能救几个是几个了
We save as many as we can.
至少用这个把她拖住
OK. Hold your own with this at least.
上面见 露丝
See you up top, Ruth.
不要等我
Don't wait for me.
你俩回到新伊甸园 去喝一杯
You two get to New Eden. Have a pint.
第一轮我请
First one's on me.
来吧 蒂尔 我们走吧
Come on, Till. Let's go.
梅兰妮和我
Melanie and I have been assigned
在不同的环境工作 因为你妈妈
separate workspaces because, well, your mother
喜欢高压的环境
likes to hold grudges.
所以你们确实在合作
So you guys are working together?
对
Oh, yes.
她无法拒绝这个拯救世界的机会
She can't help but jump at the chance to save the world
即便是和我一起
even if it's with me.
现在不必一直担心她的死活了 这种感觉很奇怪
It's weird not having to wonder all the time if she's dead or alive.
这曾是你最爱做的事
Used to be your favorite pastime.
你在新伊甸园做的事
What you did in New Eden, rerouting Big Alice's
重置大爱丽丝的供电线路 为全镇供电
power supply to generate output for the whole town,
简直是一项壮举
it's nothing short of magnificent.
只不过是弹出了离合器 就像你在芝加哥教我的一样
I just popped the clutch like you taught me in Chicago.
可那些聪明才智 我们只能先放一边了
It's a shame we have to scrap all that ingenuity.
梅兰妮知道你要偷走莉安娜吗
Did Melanie know about your plan to steal Liana?
她也参与了吗
Was she a part of it?
看来你还是不相信她
You're still trying to figure her out, aren't you?
此路不通
Dead end.
我们找部电梯
Let's find an elevator.
好
All right.
这是梅兰妮的实验室吗
Is this Mel's lab?
不知道 也许他们骗了我们
Well, maybe they lied to us.
也许她就在里面
Maybe she's behind there.
也许亚历克斯就在里面
Or Alex could be.
好吧 咱们进去吧
OK. Let's keep moving.
走
Let's go.
你们果然逃出来了
Oh, making a break for it, are we?
我以为你一个人做不到呢 本
I didn't think you had it in you, Ben, to do it on your own.
你一直都像个追随者
You've always been more of a follower.
本 她在哪儿
Yes, Ben. Where is she?
她不在这里
She's not here.
我们得走了
We gotta go.
我要留下 亚历克斯
I'm staying. Alex.
听我说
There's a restricted stairwell
大厅尽头有一个楼梯间 旁边是一个破损的消防箱
at the end of the hall. It's next to a busted firebox.
那里有个通道
It has tunnel access.
你们可以绕过进气口 直接进入顶层
You can bypass intake and go straight to the top.
祝好运
Good luck.
我告诉你妈妈 我想她
Tell your mother I miss her. We gotta go.
快走
Let's go.
我们要上去了 准备发车 以防不测
We're moving up departure as a safety precaution.
完成补给转移后 激活喷气系统
Finish the supply transfer and pull the jetway.
别管筒仓情况如何 都要在十分钟启动列车
Whatever's happening in the Silo, we need wheels up in 10 minutes.
你联系上另一个火车头了吗
Did you reach anyone in the other Engine?
我们之前把他们都撤走了 长官
Wilford cleared them all out earlier, sir.
继续尝试
Keep trying.
好的 长官 你跟我来
On it, sir. You're with me.
是 长官
Yes, sir.
我们去搜查下层列车 把大爱丽丝锁起来
We'll sweep the sub-train and lock up Big Alice.
我们不能失去她
We can't afford to lose her.
启动紧急发车
Emergency departure initiated.
你也听到了吗
Are you with me, Till?
是
Yeah.
我们得找到那个消防箱
We got to find that firebox.
抱歉
Sorry.
这边
Here.
紧急发车 雪国列车十分钟后出发
Emergency departure initiated. Snowpiercer will be leaving in 10 minutes.
谢谢你 亚历克斯
Thank you, Alex.
马上联系米利厄斯
Get Milius on the phone now.
我们有信号了 长官
We have it covered, sir.
把她给我看住了
Don't let her out of your sight.
你能给我看下喷气系统的情况吗
Can you get me eyes on the jetway?
你需要后退
You need to back off.
别废话了 他们已经逃跑了
They're scuttling away as we speak.
这里没你说话的份儿
You have no authority here.
那是我的列车
That's my train!
雪国列车十分钟后出发
Snowpiercer will depart...
快走 快
Go, go, go, go!
继续往前走
Keep it moving.
动作快点
Let's go.
本 出什么事了 你把出发提前了
Ben, what's going on? They just moved up departure.
我们得开走大爱丽丝 特里斯坦和露丝还在里面
We're taking Big Alice. But Tristan, Ruth is still in there.
我能撑多久就撑多久
I'll hold as long as I can.
好的
Good man.
这是在演习吗？
Is this a drill?
后退
Mask up.
雪国列车十分钟后出发
Snowpiercer will be departing in three minutes.
我得知道我要去哪
I need to know where I'm going.
是啊 你得告诉我 要把我带到哪里去
Y'all have to tell me where you're taking me right now.
放开我
Get off me, man.
Get off!
继续走
Keep walking.
雪国列车将在一分钟后出发
Snowpiercer will be departing in one minute.
继续往前走
Keep moving!
一直走到后面
All the way to the back.
大家快点 我们走
Let's hustle, everyone. Let's go. Let's go.
快走 快
Come on. Hustle up.
继续往前
Keep going.
你想做什么
What do you need?
将军就要来了 但我们需要更多时间断开连接
The admiral is coming but we need more time to disconnect.
好 我给你争取点时间
All right. We'll buy you some.
凯莉 跟着我
Tailies with me.
快点 快点 快点
Let's go. Let's go.
泰勒 我们走吧 来吧
Till, let's get out of here. Come on.
走
Let's move.
快
Go.
把门打开
Open the hatch.
该死
God damn it.
快点
Let's move.
什么问题
What's the problem?
入口有问题 我们到不了顶部
There's something blocking the exits. We can't get up top. Out of my way.
好 这样能行 继续走
Yeah. That'll work. Keep going.
从别的门口进去
Get to the other hatches.
走 快点
Go, go, go, go. Hurry.
好了 我们得换舵
All right. We need to switch helms.
有三个按钮 按下中控台显示器后面的前三个按钮
There's three buttons. The first three buttons behind that monitor
按下去
in the center console... press them.
哪个开关
Which switch?
前三个开关 按一下就会变成绿色 在左边
The first three switches. They'll turn green when you press them. To the left.
呃 按了
Ah, one.
好的
OK.
可以了
Got it.
真棒
Nice.
我在雪国列车上留了后门程序
I left a back door open on Snowpiercer.
我看看它还在不在
Let's see if it's still there.
喷气系统将在十秒后启动 十 九
Jetway will breach in 10, 9,
八 七 再给我一分钟 拜托
8, 7...If I could just get another minute, please, a minute.
崔斯坦 快
Tristan. Tristan!
雪国列车将于...
Snowpiercer will depart...
你真是个好人 真的
Oh, you're a good man, Tristan, truly.
都是跟你们学的
I learned from the best.
收到了
Got it.
谢谢
Thanks. Yeah.
我不知道泰勒能坚持多久
I don't know how much longer the Tailies can hold them off.
我只希望在断开连接之前 雪国列车不要出意外
I just wish there was a way of Snowpiercer not following us once we release.
糟了 他们在把我们拉走
Shit. They're pulling us.
准备好脱钩了吗
Are we good to release?
你准备好了吗 好了
You ready? Yeah.
准备好了
I'm ready.
糟糕
Oh, shit.
发生了什么
What's happening?
没有脱钩成功
It's not releasing.
肯定是把我们关起来时
They must have compromised the coupling system
他们破坏了耦合系统
while we were still captive or maybe
或者这是改造的一部分
it's part of the retrofit.
也就是说我们被困住了
Does that mean we're stuck?
本 是不是意味着我们被困住了
Ben, does that mean we're stuck?
天啊
Oh my god.
所以 新伊甸园的每个人 奥德丽
So everyone in New Eden, Audrey, they're...
他们都会死的
they're all going to die.
They're just going to die.
也许还有别的办法 从雪国列车那边
There might be a way from the Snowpiercer side.
子列车
The sub-train.
他们可以通过手动控制绕过电子系统
I can bypass the electrical controls with a manual override.
我们得把你和大爱丽丝送回新伊甸园
OK. We need to get you and Big Alice back to New Eden.
我不会离开你的
I'm not leaving you.
我会没事的
I'll be OK.
而且 这里还有梅兰妮
Besides, Mel's here.
还有亚历克斯
So is Alex.
我会没事的
I'll be fine.
一定还有别的办法
There has to be another way.
我觉得没有
I don't think there is.
你不会是对我心软了吧
Not getting soft on me, are you?
不
No.
很好
Good.
我们走
Let's go.
太好了 迈尔斯可以指挥
Right. Miles can pilot us.
我们封锁了三等舱的舱门 迫使大家回到列车
We blocked all the hatches in third. Forced them back uptrain.
很好
Good work.
我只要拉动几个杠杆
I'm going to pull a couple of levers.
大爱丽丝就自由了 你就能回新伊甸园了
Big Alice will be free and off to New Eden you'll go.
看看那边的情况怎么样
See what all the fuss is about.
我会给你寄明信片的
I'll send you a postcard.
来了 大家扶稳了
This is it! Hold on!
快点 工程师
Come on, Engineer!
我们走
Let's go!
快
Come on.
等等
Stop.
让我们出去
Let us out.
抓紧了
Just hang on.
露丝 你来了
Ruth, you made it.
我什么都找不到
I couldn't find the others.
发生了什么
What's happening?
因为本在给雪国列车搞破坏 这样他们就追不上我们了
It's just Ben sabotaging Snowpiercer so they can't follow us.
好 很好 然后我们就会脱钩
Good. Good. And then we'll uncouple.
联结器卡住了 但本会启动手动控制
The coupling's jammed, but Ben's going to just pull the manual override.
但我们没有冰封服
But we don't have any breach suits.
你什么意思
What do you mean?
手动控制 是要户外操作的
The manual override, it's outside.
糟了 不
Shit! No. No. No. No!
不
No. No.
No!
本
Ben!
不
No! No!
No!
不
No.
他做到了
He did it.
不
No. No.
走吧 迈尔斯
Let's go, Miles.
继续
Go on.
你还在这里
You're still here.
没人告诉我发生了什么
Nobody will tell me what happened.
跟着我
Follow me
我会带你找到正确的道路
I'll show you the way
嘘
Shh.
不要动
Don't move.
莉安娜在哪儿
Where's Liana?
她还好吗
Is she OK?
对不起 乔西
Oh, I'm sorry, Josie.
莉安娜挺好的
There's nothing wrong with Liana.
今天之前我们做了个交易
Earlier today, you and I made a deal.
用你的女儿交换大爱丽丝
Your daughter in exchange for Big Alice.
你没有履行承诺
You didn't hold up your end of the bargain.
幸运的是 我是个正直的人
Lucky for you, I'm a man of integrity.
我说话算数 尽管我的回报为零
I stick to my word, despite getting nothing in return.
你是新伊甸园那边的 对吧
You're from New Eden, right?
你有流鼻血的症状吗
Do you ever get nosebleeds?
你对我做了什么
What have you done to me?
我的样貌如此美丽
The beauty of me
看来我们有很多要谈的
It seems we have a lot to talk about.
我是尼莫·罗素博士
I'm Dr. Nima Rousseau.
我是你母亲的老朋友了
I'm an old... I'm an old friend of your mother's.
我相信 一切都会好起来的
I've always believed that everything would be all right.
这次情况不一样
This time is different.
告诉我们罗被关在哪里
Just tell us where Roche is being held.
怎么回事
What's going on?
莉安娜在哪
Where's Liana?
现在可真精彩 约瑟夫
That's a hell of a story, Joseph.
出了点状况
There was an incident.
让你尝尝我的厉害
You should have taken the bullet.